Senator & Mrs. Whitney N. Seymour Jr. Papers: Records Relating to the Storm King Case, 1962-1978
Marist College Archives and Special Collections
- 4. Printed Matter, 1962 - 1969; 4; 0.6 Linear Feet Boxes: 7 - 8
  - (HRVC) Rules and Regulations for Project Review, July 1967 (Folder 35, Box 7)
  - Program for Lawyers Committee for Civil Rights Under Law (Folder 36, Box 7)
  - The Community Committee - The Brooklyn Museum - Dates to Remember (Folder 37, Box 7)
  - The Hudson - Historic Sites - State of New York Hudson River Valley Commission (Folder 1, Box 8)
  - The Hudson - Summary Report of the Hudson River Valley Commission (Folder 2, Box 8)
  - The Hudson - Biological Resources - State of New York HRVC (Folder 3, Box 8)
  - The Hudson - Water Resources State of N.Y., HRVC (Folder 4, Box 8)
  - Panorama of the Hudson (Folder 5, Box 8)
  - HRVC Newsletter - Vol. No. 6-9 (Folder 6, Box 8)
  - The Water Resources of New York State (Folder 7, Box 8)
  - Hudson River Valley Commission Act (Chapter 345, Laws of 1966 as Amended) (Folder 8, Box 8)
  - The Hudson River Valley Commission Annual Report, 1967 (Folder 9, Box 8)
  - The Hudson - Archeological Sites, State of New York HRVC (Folder 10, Box 8)
  - The Hudson Population - State of New York HRVC (Folder 11, Box 8)
  - Break Through to the Hudson River (Folder 12, Box 8)
  - Session Laws - 189th Session, 1966 (Folder 13, Box 8)
  - Recreation Proposal - Cornwall Pumped Storage Project (Folder 14, Box 8)
  - Atomic Power For the Empire State (Folder 15, Box 8)
  - “Freedom to Breathe” Report of the Mayor’s Task Force (Folder 16, Box 8)
  - Holiday - The Hudson River (Folder 17, Box 8)
- 5. Legal Material, 1965 - 1969; 5; 0.3 Linear Feet Box: 9
  Briefs, petitions, motions, and other legal documents submitted by Scenic Hudson and others; testimony before the Federal Power Commission; and related materials.
  Roughly chronological
  - A Bill to Provide for the Establishment of the Hudson Highlands…1/8/65 (Folder 1, Box 9)
  - F.P.C. Opinion&Order Issuing License and Reopening and Remanding Proceeding…Issued 3/9/65 (Folder 2, Box 9)
  - Application for Rehearing of Opinion&Order Issuing License, Petition to Reopen Hearings, 4/8/65 (Folder 3, Box 9)
  - Anadromous Fish 1965, Hearings on Hudson River Spawning Grounds, May 10&11, 1965 (Folder 4, Box 9)
  - SHPC Vs. FPC&Con Ed, No. 106 Sept. Term, 1965 (Folder 5, Box 9)
  - Case Sent Back for Rehearing, 3/11/66 (Folder 6, Box 9)
  - Information Sheet, Senate Power line Hearings, May 4-6, 1966 (Folder 7, Box 9)
  - Con Ed Amendment to Application for License, Project #2338, Before the FPC, May 1966 (Folder 8, Box 9)
  - Before the Public Service Commission of the State of Missouri, Interim Report and Order (Folder 9, Box 9)
  - Project #2338 - Response of Con Ed to SHPC Motion of 12/14/66 to Postpone Hearings (Folder 10, Box 9)
  - SHPC Withdrawal of Motion to Postpone Hearings of 11/21/66 (Folder 11, Box 9)
  - SHPC Brief, 12/15/66 (Folder 12, Box 9)
  - Statement by Sen. Seymour before the HRVC, 4/3/67 (Folder 13, Box 9)
  - An Act Concerning Petitions by the State Board of Fisheries…to Oppose the Cornwall NY Hydroelectric Plant, 6/5/67 (State of Connecticut) (Folder 14, Box 9)
  - Brief of Sierra Club&Its Atlantic Chapter, 8/14/67 (Folder 15, Box 9)
  - Reply Brief of Sierra Club&Its Atlantic Chapter, 9/5/67 (Folder 16, Box 9)
  - Presiding Examiner’s Initial Decision in Remanded Proceedings on an Application for a License Under Part I of the Federal Power Act, 8/6/68 (Folder 17, Box 9)
  - Brief on Behalf of SHPC, 10/7/68 (Folder 18, Box 9)
  - Brief on Behalf of SHPC, Intervenor on Exceptions to the Initial Decision of Hon. Ewing G. Simpson, 10/28/68 (Folder 19, Box 9)
  - SHPC - Point One of the Brief on Behalf of SHPC to FPC (Folder 20, Box 9)
  - Project 2338, Motion for Oral Argument, 10/28/68 (Folder 21, Box 9)
  - Report on Pre Conference Hearing, Washington D.C., 1/16/69 (Folder 22, Box 9)
  - SHPC Vs. Army Corps of Engineers, 12/28/73 (Folder 23, Box 9)
  - Quotes From Washington Hearings (Folder 24, Box 9)
  - Washington Memorandum - Senate Hearings on Burial of Transmission Lines (Folder 25, Box 9)
  - Resolution - Senate, Seymour Paterson (Folder 26, Box 9)
  - FPC Project #2338 - Prepared Testimony of Jerome Wyckoff (Folder 27, Box 9)
  - A Bill - To Provide for the Establishment of the Hudson National Scenic River way in New York (Folder 28, Box 9)
  - Lower Hudson River Valley Heritage Commission - Legislative Intent (Folder 29, Box 9)
  - Resolution Memorializing Congress to Establish the Hudson Highlands National Park (Folder 30, Box 9)
  - …And From Some Briefs Filed by Important Groups (Folder 31, Box 9)
  - Schedule of Public Hearings (Folder 32, Box 9)
- 6. Statements, Radio & TV Reports, Releases, Magazine Articles, Memos, 1965 - 1969; 6; 0.3 Linear Feet Box: 10
  Statements, Radio & TV Reports, Releases, Magazine Articles, Memos.
  - Statement Relating to Con Ed Increase in Air Pollution…by Alexander Lurkis, 7/28/65 (Folder 1, Box 10)
  - Summary Report of HRVC, 2/1/66 (Folder 2, Box 10)
  - HRVC Rules and Regulations for Project Review, 2/24/67 (Folder 3, Box 10)
  - Subchapter B, HRVC Rules&Regulations for Project Review, April 1967 (Folder 4, Box 10)
  - Special Report - Utilities&The Hudson River, 7/27/69 (Folder 5, Box 10)
  - A Report to the People of NYC&Westchester County, Charles Luce, Chairman Con Ed (Folder 6, Box 10)
  - The Issue at Storm King Mountain (Folder 7, Box 10)
  - The Hudson River, For Whose Utility? (Folder 8, Box 10)
  - Alternative to Con Ed’s Ten-Year Program to Meet Growing Energy Needs…by Alexander Lurkis (Folder 9, Box 10)
  - Potential Recreation Resources of the Hudson Highlands &Black Rock Forest (Folder 10, Box 10)
  - Errata Sheet for - “Report on the Hudson River and its Tributaries” (Folder 11, Box 10)
  - Con Ed’s Ten Year Program to Meet Growing Energy Needs &Reduce Air Pollution (Folder 12, Box 10)
  - Cornwall Economic Studies Comparison of Fossil Fuel Usage (Folder 13, Box 10)
  - Recommendation in the Bureau of Outdoor Recreation Report (Folder 14, Box 10)
  - Magazine Article “The Storm King Opinion” 3/66 (Folder 15, Box 10)
  - Vassar Alumnae Magazine, April 1966 (Folder 16, Box 10)
  - The New Yorker “The Talk of the Town” 1/7/67 (Folder 17, Box 10)
  - Ramparts “Everybody Should Break an Ankle” 4/67 (Folder 18, Box 10)
  - Clean Up the Hudson “Keep America Beautiful” June 1967 (Folder 19, Box 10)
  - Electrical World, 10/23/67 (Folder 20, Box 10)
  - “The Hudson River&Its Fisheries” 12/68 (Folder 21, Box 10)
  - Trail Walker, Jan. - Feb. 1969 (Folder 22, Box 10)
  - Outdoor Life, Jan. 1969 (Folder 23, Box 10)
  - America the Formerly Beautiful, 2/69 (Folder 24, Box 10)
  - New York “Does Con Ed Deserve a Rate Hike?” 9/8/69 (Folder 25, Box 10)
  - Forbes Magazine (Folder 26, Box 10)
  - Ramparts “America the Raped” (Folder 27, Box 10)
  - “This Hollowed Out Ground” Carl Carmer (Folder 28, Box 10)
  - CCA News - The Nuclear Bomb in Your Own Backyard (Folder 29, Box 10)
  - “Precedent on the Hudson” Maxwell C. Wheat Jr. (Folder 30, Box 10)
  - Press Release, 1/18/65 (Folder 31, Box 10)
  - WMCA Editorial, Storm King Mountain, 2/13/65 (Folder 32, Box 10)
  - WMCA Editorial, Storm King Mountain, 2/4/65 (Folder 33, Box 10)
  - Issue - Scrambled Eggs - Fish Meal at Storm King, 3/15/66 (Folder 34, Box 10)
  - For Immediate Release, SHPC, 4/28/66 (Folder 35, Box 10)
  - Release - Mayor Lindsay, 5/18/66 (Folder 36, Box 10)
  - Senator Mansfield’s Statement Concerning HR 13508, 9/13/66 (Folder 37, Box 10)
  - Release - Senator Seymour, 3/6/67 (Folder 38, Box 10)
  - Radio&T.V. Reports - Martha Deane Show, 5/16/67 (Folder 39, Box 10)
  - WMCA Opinion - Storm King Mountain #5, Aug. 20-21, 1967 (Folder 40, Box 10)
  - WMCA Opinion - Reply by William Farley for Con Ed, Aug. 27- 28, 1967 (Folder 41, Box 10)
  - WMCA Opinion - Storm King Mountain #6, Aug. 29-30, 1967 (Folder 42, Box 10)
  - WMCA Opinion - Reply by William Farley re: Storm King #6, Sept. 1-3, 1967 (Folder 43, Box 10)
  - Con Ed Release, 9/27/67 (Folder 44, Box 10)
  - Con Ed Release, 8/6/68 (Folder 45, Box 10)
  - F.P.C. Release, 11/19/68 (Folder 46, Box 10)
  - Radio&T.V. Reports Inc. Hearings on Alternative Sites for Con Ed Plant, 3/8/69 (Folder 47, Box 10)
  - Release - FPC/Con Ed, 11/19/68 (Folder 48, Box 10)
  - Radio&T.V. Reports - SHPC Opposes Second Site Proposed by Con Ed…3/17/69 (Folder 49, Box 10)
  - Statement of Governor Nelson A. Rockefeller - Regarding Hudson Highlands State Park (Folder 50, Box 10)
  - Release - Senator Seymour, 4/3/? (Folder 51, Box 10)
  - Memo to Hon. John V. Lindsay - from Norman Cousins, May 1966 (Folder 52, Box 10)
  - Memo - Jim Cope, 2/12/67 (Folder 53, Box 10)
  - Memo to Jim Cope&Rod Vandivert from H. Lyon, 2/14/67 (Folder 54, Box 10)
  - Memo to Jim Cope&Rod Vandivert from Horace Lyon, 5/15/67 (Folder 55, Box 10)
  - Memo to N.Y.S. Members&Cooperators - from the Wilderness Society, 10/28/68 (Folder 56, Box 10)
  - Interoffice Memo to Stephen Duggan from T.W. Cashel, 4/15/69 (Folder 57, Box 10)
  - Memo Re: “The Truth” (Folder 58, Box 10)
  - The Appalachians Highlands Preserve Compact - Supporting Memorandum (Folder 59, Box 10)
  - Memorandum Concerning the Purported Financial Advantages of the Con Ed Storm King Project (Folder 60, Box 10)
  - Memo to Mike Seymour from Nancy Mathews re: Miss Circle Line (Folder 61, Box 10)
- 7. Subject Files & Misc., 7; 0.3 Linear Feet Box: 11
  Series contains information on a variety of topics relating to the Storm King Case. Subjects include Breezy Point, Olana, Glossary of Terms, Transmission Lines, Fisheries, Dams, and Maps..
  By subject
  - Glossary of Terms (Folder 1, Box 11)
  - Air Pollution (Folder 2, Box 11)
  - Progress Towards Pure Waters, 3/28/66 (Folder 3, Box 11)
  - Pure Waters Program “Well of the World” Water Pollution (Folder 4, Box 11)
  - Conference on International&Interstate Regulation of water Pollution, March 12-13, 1970 (Folder 5, Box 11)
  - Private Marinas&Yacht Clubs on the Hudson River between Ellis Island and Troy (Folder 6, Box 11)
  - General Electric Ad (Folder 7, Box 11)
  - Con Ed Rates - Past Record (Folder 8, Box 11)
  - State/Local/Federal Participation in Total Projects Costs of Pure Waters Program - Lower Hudson&Its Tributaries (Folder 9, Box 11)
  - Daily Variation Patterns on Weekdays, Saturdays& Sundays for Carbon Monoxide&Sulfur Dioxide (Folder 10, Box 11)
  - The Power Plants Threat to Marine Life (Folder 11, Box 11)
  - Big Bird Watcher’s Argument (Folder 12, Box 11)
  - Citizens Committee for the Hudson Valley - Statement of Purpose (Folder 13, Box 11)
  - Breezy Point (Folder 14, Box 11)
  - Save the Hudson (Folder 15, Box 11)
  - Transmission Lines (Folder 16, Box 11)
  - Fisheries (Folder 17, Box 11)
  - Future Recreation Needs of the New York Metropolitan Region (Folder 18, Box 11)
  - Alternative Power - Jets/Nuclear (Folder 19, Box 11)
  - Dams - Geological (Folder 20, Box 11)
  - Olana (Folder 21, Box 11)
  - Future Recreation Needs of the New York Metropolitan Area (Folder 22, Box 11)
  - Maps (Folder 23, Box 11)
  - Photographs&Images (Folder 24, Box 11)